CHEN Zheng
liamchzh@gmail.com
Melbourne, VIC, Australia

Summary

Over the past nearly 3 years, I've been working on developing News Feed system of Zhihu, which supports more than ten millions of users. I am experienced in API development and performance enhancement. I am looking for a Python developer position where my skills can be used in designing, developing and optimizing web applications and their performance.

Technical Skill

Programming Languages: Python, PHP, Hive, Apache Pig

Operating Systems: Linux, Mac OS X

Data Base: MySQL, Redis, Cassandra, TokuMX

Framework: Tornado, Flask

Version Control: Git

Experience

API Developer & Traveler Feb 2017 - Present

Now I am taking a gap year, Melbourne is the first city to stay. While exploring this city, I work remotely as a backend developer for a startup company in China.

Web Developer, Zhihu Inc. March 2014 - January 2017

- Work on News Feed team, maintaining a system that supports more than ten millions
 of users, diversifying the content of top stories and enhancing the performance.
- Manage engineering design, development and implementation of the services and backend API.
- Monitor quality metrics of user behavior, collecting more than a billion lines of log everyday.
- Calculate specific interests of each individual user through analysing data with Hive and Apache Pig, making the stories more relevant and engaging.

Web Developer Intern, Yiyan Inc. Sep 2013 - Feb 2014

- Rewrite the website, migrate from PHP to Python.
- Design and maintain databases.

Education

2010 - 2014 Bachelor of Software Engineering, Beijing Institute of Technology.